<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zvi Biener</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://zbiener.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://zbiener.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Searching BibDesk with Alfred</title>
        <description>
          
          If you use Alfred (see here) and BibDesk (see here), you might find the following useful. The script below uses Alfred’s “Workflow” feature. It provides a set of commands to search bibliographical entries directly from Alfred, and execute a variety of actions related to citing, opening PDFs, narrowing searches, etc....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/searching-bibdesk</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/searching-bibdesk</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Find Everything with Alfred</title>
        <description>
          
          Alfred is like Mac’s Spotlight on steroids. Its an application launcher, an emailer, an iTunes controller, a weather report, a search tool, and much more. It finds things on your computer, but it also makes doing things on your computer much quicker. The basic idea behind Alfred is simple: you...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/everything-in-its-place</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/everything-in-its-place</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Keeping Track of Documents and Bibliographies</title>
        <description>
          
          Bibliographies for small projects are easy. But they are complicated and time-consuming for larger projects. You should use a bibliography manager. Zotero is free and flexible. Papers is swanky but overrated (IMO). I discuss BibDesk below. It is open-source, easy, and very configurable. I started using BibDesk years ago, when...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/bibliographies</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/bibliographies</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Author's Text vs. Reader's Text, Part 2</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is about the feature of Scrivener I use most frequently. It is the ability to separate the author’s text from the reader’s text on a sentence-by-sentence level. The basic idea is that Scrivener allows you to specify chunks of text as “Annotations” and then control whether those annotations...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/author-text2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/author-text2</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Author's Text vs. Reader's Text, Part I</title>
        <description>
          
          One of the greatest benefits of Scrivener is the ability differentiate between the text the author sees and the text the reader sees. In programs like Word and Pages, this can only be done by using the “comments” mechanism. Comments, however, can only (easily) handle a subset of the kinds...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/author-text1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/author-text1</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Scrivener is Awesome (And So Can You!)</title>
        <description>
          
          (Revised 9/03/2019) Scrivener is worth every penny. In fact, it’s the only piece of software I suggest students buy. Everything else I use is open-source. In this post, I’ll list why I use Scrivener. In later posts, I’ll provide more detailed instructions. I use Scrivener because it encourages the user...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/scrivener-is-awesome</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/scrivener-is-awesome</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Use a Three-Ring Binder</title>
        <description>
          
          Lets start simple. Paper works. ​Tools: Three Ring Binder. Hole punch. Post-It Notes. Organization: I use one binder (rarely more) for each article-sized project. Each binder contains three main areas: Long-term notes Primary Texts Secondary texts I use the Post-It notes as tabs. It makes tabs easily replaceable and cheap....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/three-ring-binder</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/three-ring-binder</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introduction: Tech Tools for Students</title>
        <description>
          
          Some academics have a “system” they use to keep track of research, writing, feedback, revisions, etc. Students can spend years figuring out what a good “system” is, partly because academics are bad at sharing, After some conversation with students, I decided to write some posts about my “system.” I recommend...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://zbiener.github.io/blog/tech-tools-for-students</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://zbiener.github.io/blog/tech-tools-for-students</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
